## Jay Lim

Jaylim106@gmail.com ❖ 310-617-4644 ❖ San Diego, CA ❖ jaylim.net ❖ Github

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY: Experienced full-stack software engineer with 2 years of proven leadership experience as a team tech lead, supporting a team of 6 individuals. Specializes in the Decision Center product at Signifyd as a subject matter expert. Consistently and timely delivers business value on projects.

## **EXPERIENCE**

Signifyd Jan 2024 - Present

Staff Software Engineer, Team Tech Lead

Remote

- Utilized Mysql8 Common Table Expression to reduce MYSQL Select p99 latency from 1.5 sec to 50 ms.
- Re-architected microservice which allowed us to scale to more customers, resulting in monthly savings exceeding \$600/month over alternative solutions while requiring minimal maintenance from engineering staff.
- Spearheaded project slashing number of engineering support tickets on customer onboarding from 10 to 0 monthly and reducing merchant time-to-go-live from 6 days to just 1.

Signifyd Jan 2022 - Jan 2024

Senior Software Engineer, Team Tech Lead

Remote

- Delivered key features for Decision Center product, scaling from 1 team and customer to over 500 teams and 220 customers over 3 years.
- Resolved user-facing 5xx errors, mitigating 70% of exceptions originating from Cassandra and 95% from AWS
   ELB. Addressed intermittent slowdowns in MySQL caused by page cleaner activity.
- Developed code generation for order history feature descriptions, a critical tool embraced by both engineers and data scientists at Signifyd. Eliminated the chance of human error caused by inaccurate feature names.

Signifyd Oct 2020 – Dec 2021

Software Engineer

Remote

- Investigated root cause of a poorly performing MYSQL query and reduced p99 latency from 1.2 sec to 50 ms.
- Led tech debt project to refactor HTTP authorization/authentication which unblocked upgrading version of Play! framework to v2.7.9.
- Consistently participated in engineering on-call rotations, adeptly resolving customer-facing incidents promptly
  and effectively, even during weekends and off-hours.

HaloSentient Sept 2018 – Aug 2020

Fullstack Developer

Remote

- Implemented mobile friendly ecommerce marketplace website using React/Redux with hooks, Node.js, Typescript, Firebase, and Stripe as the payment processor.
- Designed and developed full stack web app using React, MongoDB and Socket.io for real-time UI updates.
- Audited (QA) for interview-based web (**Angular/Node.js**) & mobile (**Swift** & **JAVA**) application by testing client & reading source code. Identified and reported multiple exploit avenues in web application.

## Education

University of California, San Diego

Chemical Engineering B.S./Computer Science minor

## **SKILLS**

- **Proficient Skills:** Typescript/Javascript; Python; Java; React; Redux; Node.js; SQL; NoSQL; gRPC; microservices; Cassandra; MongoDB; Linux; Git; Apache/Nginx; AWS; GCP; Express.js; VIM; Functional Programming; OpenAPI
- Familiar Skills: Gradle; Airflow; Golang; Play! Framework; PHP; Docker; K8s; C; C++; Angular; Flask; SASS; Matlab;